### **General Info:**

Name: Neil Dykes

Date of birth: 28th February 1991

**KSA Mobile:** +966 54 158 8477

UK Mobile: +00 44 7818 528657

Email: neild 1991@hotmail.co.uk

Status: Single

Location: Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

Nationality: United Kingdom

Availability: Available from Monday 6th January 2020

## **Education, Qualifications and Training:**

**Liverpool John Moores University** 2009 – 2012

BSc in Quantity Surveying (hons) - 2:1

West Derby School - Sixth Form

2007 - 2009

A-Levels – Business Studies (B), Economics (C), ICT (B), General Studies (A)

#### West Derby School.

2002 - 2007

13 GCSEs- Art & Design at grade A and Mathematics, English Lit, English Language, Business and ICT at Grade B, 5 others at grade C or above

Additional industry training received on COINS OA, COINS Plus, SAP and inControl.

# Personal Profile:

Committed, self-motivated and driven, I am a Commercial Professional who believes in continuous improvement and is always looking to grasp new opportunities, constantly stretching myself to develop and grow in line with the evolving industry and its aspirations. I can develop and build strong relationships, this is utilised to adopt a flexible and collaborative approach to delivering the task at hand. My positive, ambitious and enthusiastic approach ensures a consistently high standard of delivery.

I have more than 7 years post education experience within post contract Commercial and Contract Management (NEC, FIDIC and Bespoke contract types) in both the United Kingdom and the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia. I am currently working for Faithful + Gould (Saudi Arabia). I have held positions both on behalf of the Contractor and Project Management Office (PMO).

My career aspirations are to continue developing and learning daily and to continue working for industry leading Construction companies and industry leading projects.

#### **Career History:**

Faithful & Gould Commercial Manager, Senior Contract Administrator, Project Senior Quantity Surveyor 2017 – Present Kingdom of Saudi Arabia

# IPND Stage 3 Project 2017 – Present

The IPND Fibre Network Project is to provide a sophisticated Fibre Internet network to 225 individual sites across the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia.

- Originally Project Senior Quantity Surveyor and later promoted into a Senior Contract Administration position and currently Commercial Manager working on behalf of the Project Management Office (PMO)
- Responsible for all the Commercial Reporting on behalf of the client including: Cost Value Reconciliation, Change Control/Management, Delay/Time monitoring, Earned Value Analysis, Contract Administration, Sub-Contract Management, Applications for payments, Cost/Cash Flow forecasting and Risk analysis/Advice

Jones Engineering Saudi Arabia Ltd MEP Quantity Surveyor 2016 - 2017 Kingdom of Saudi Arabia

# Almarai CPP2 & CPP3 Processing Plant Projects

The Almarai CPP2 & CPP3 Processing Plants Projects are two dairy products processing plants in Al Kharj, Saudi Arabia. The largest dairy processing plants in the world.

- MEP Quantity Surveyor on the projects reporting directly into Senior Commercial Manager
- Responsible for all on-site Commercial activities for the MEP package including; Cost Value Reconciliation, Cost Comparisons, Submitting of Variations, Sub-Contract Management, Applications for Payment, advising Project Management on Contractual implications of intended courses of action, Contract Administration, delay monitoring, Monthly Margin Reviews, Cost / Cash Flow Forecasting, Managing others and Risk analysis/advice

Laing O'Rourke (Crown House Technologies)
MEP Quantity Surveyor
2014 – 2015
United Kingdom

## Glan Clwyd Hospital Redevelopment Project

The Glan Clwyd Hospital Redevelopment is a large health care refurbishment project in North Wales. Working under the NEC 3 Option C contract.

- MEP Quantity Surveyor on the project, reporting to part time Senior Commercial Manager
- Responsible for all Quantity Surveying duties of the MEP package including; Cost Value reconciliation, preparation of interim applications for payment and internal valuations,

measurement, valuations, interim administration and settlement of sub-contract accounts, client facing responsibilities, advising project management on contractual implications of intended courses of action, advising on commercial risks within the project, preparation and hosting of monthly contract reviews, preparation of monthly management account submissions and change control management and recovery

#### **Chester Zoo Islands Project**

The Chester Zoo Islands project is an extension to the historic Chester Zoo recreational facility. The project extended the Zoo to allow for additional animals to inhabit.

- MEP Quantity Surveyor on the project, reporting in to Regional Commercial leader
- Responsible for all aspects of the cost management of all aspects of the project including labour, plant, materials and subcontract packages, amongst others. Key roles and responsibilities include agreement of final accounts, liaison with the Client, internal cost reporting and change management. NEC 3 Option A contract

H.E.Simm & Sons Assistant MEP Quantity Surveyor 2012 - 2014 United Kingdom

# Various New Build / Refurbishment Projects

- MEP Assistant Quantity Surveyor within a team responsible for Commercially delivering various developments across North West, England
- Directly responsible for all aspects of Commercial Management of Sub Contract packages.
   Roles and responsibilities include agreement of Contract Documents, Procurement of Sub-Contracts, through to agreement of final accounts, and liaison with the Client and internal cost reporting and change management

### Other:

- I hold both (full & clean) UK and KSA driving licences
- I hold a valid KSA Igama
- References available upon request